♪〜
〜♪
（地鳴り）
（ごう音）
（ミリィ･トンプソン）先輩 あれ！
Ma'am, look!
（メリル･ストライフ）えっ？
（ごう音）
（カレン）メリル メリル
Meryl? Meryl?
メリルってば
Meryl!
（メリル）あっ…
あ… カレン
Oh, Karen.
（カレン）
ハア… 極上のサボり方ね
When you loaf,
you loaf in style.
アハハ
I travelled around for so many months,
I haven't regained my land legs.
何か月も旅を続けてましたから
感覚が戻らなくって
You were a witness to
the 5th moon incident.
（マーク）
なんたって フィフスムーン事件の
目撃者だもんな
When you saw a hole put in the moon
before your very eyes, how did it feel?
目の前で月に穴を開けられたとき
どんな気分だった？
Don't talk about it
like some tourist.
物見遊山(ものみゆさん)みたいなこと言わないで
You're talking to someone who
spent 5 months on the outside...
アウターを走り回って５か月の旅よ
...with the walking danger zone
who's been labelled an Act of God!
それも 人間災害に指定された
超危険人物と
It's a miracle she
came back alive at all!
生きて戻れただけでも
奇跡なんだから 実際
Yes, but...
（メリル）でも…
（カレン）うん？
...but it wasn't as bad
as all that.
でも 言われるほど
ひどい経験じゃありませんでしたわ
Sure, there was some danger...
確かに危ない目にも遭いましたけど
ヴァッシュさんは
思っているより—
...but Vash was more of a
regular guy than you think.
人間として ごく
まともな方でしたから
Now see here, Meryl...
あのね メリル
そんなこと言ってて—
...you're the one who gets handed
all the odd jobs because of that.
便利に使われてるのは
あなたなのよ
I know you're good at what you do,
but if you keep risking your life...
有能なのは結構だけど—
命の懸かった荒事に
女の幸せはないと思うの　私
...you'll never achieve
womanly happiness!
What time is it now?
（部長）今は何の時間かなあ？
（カレン）いっ…
（マーク）がっ！
お… おはようございます 部長
G-Good morning, Chief!
Meryl, could I
see you a moment?
（部長）
メリル君 ちょっといいか？
Sir?
は… はあ？
WHAT?
（メリル）ええーっ！
（マイク）ほお？
（カレン）うん？
ミリィ
Milly?
Milly, where are you?
（メリル）
ミリィ どこにいますの？
Good morning, ma'am!
（ミリィ）
おはようございます 先輩
（メリル）ぐっ…
いつの間に転職しましたの？
When did you change vocation?
I'm being punished for coming
in late 20 times in a row.
20回連続で遅刻したバツなんです
You never change, do you?
相変わらずですわね
…って仕事ですわよ 仕事
We have a job!
Vash the Stampede
appeared in LittleJersey!
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードが—
リトルジャージーに
現れたんですのよ
じゃあ
ヴァッシュさん生きてるんだ！
Then he's alive!
Aren't you glad, ma'am?!
よかったですね 先輩
（メリル）ウフッ
It is no cause
for gladness!
ちっ ちっともよくありませんわ
We have to stop him before
he stirs up trouble, or else!
あの人がトラブルを起こす前に
止めないと—
大変なことになりますわよ
（メリル）さっ 行きますわよ
Come on, let's get going.
Hold on a second...
You're way too fast!
（ミリィ）
ちょ… ちょっと待ってください
むっちゃ 早いですよ
（メリル）まったく…
For crying out loud. If he's alive,
he could at least mention it.
生きてたら生きてたって
言えばいいのに
He probably gets a kick out of
making people eat his dust...
こうやって 人を煙(けむ)に巻いて
楽しんでるんですわ
...the jerk.
きっと
（カレン）メリル！
Meryl?!
I'll bring you back
an Epipy bag!
（メリル）お土産は
エピピのバッグにしますわ
（バスのドアが閉まる音）
まあ いっか…
Oh, well...
（カレン）女の子だって—
...sometimes girls need
to risk their lives, Meryl.
命を懸けなきゃいけないことが
あるわよね
メリル
Hey, if you're dead,
you don't have to say anything...
（運転手）おい
死んでるんなら
黙っててもいいが—
...but if you're alive,
speak to me!
生きてるなら返事をしろ
I'll give you a lift.
乗してってやるぜ
（２人）
ああ… お願いします
Oh, bless you!
（ニコラス･Ｄ･ウルフウッド）
ぷはー 生き返ったで
I'm alive!
（ヴァッシュの のどが鳴る音）
How come I run into so much
trouble when you're around?
お前とおると—
なんで
トラブルが絶えへんのんや？
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
ガハハハ　君が無計画すぎるの
You're too unmethodical!
Normally when you buy an old, used
bike, you're supposed to repair it...
中古屋で買いたたいた
ボロバイクを—
ろくな整備もしないまま
走ったりする？ 普通
...before riding it!
Are you dissing
my Angelina II?!
わいのアンジェリーナ２号に
ケチつける気か？
I'm dissing you,
not the bike!!
バイクじゃなくて
君に言ってんの 君に！
Say again,
Needle-noggin?
何やと？ このトンガリ
Who you callin'
a Needle-noggin?!
誰がトンガリだ 誰が
お前以外に誰がおる
Who else?!
（ヴァッシュ）
うーん… ああ…
（２人）あーっ！
（ウルフウッド）
な… なんちゅうことすんねん
Now look what you've done!!
- So it's my fault?!
- That's right!!!
（ヴァッシュ）
僕のせいか？ 僕のせいか？
（ウルフウッド）そうやあ！
Be quiet,
or I'll throw you off!
静かにしねえと放り出すぞ！
（２人）あ… はいはい
Sorry, sir.
So, where do you want to go?
…で どこに行きたいんだ？
（ヴァッシュ）カンサス
（ウルフウッド）ニューオレゴン
- Kansas!
- New Oregon!
（ヴァッシュ）ん？
（ウルフウッド）えっ？
Why there?! Aren't we investigating
the town with the disappearances?!
何でやねん
失踪事件のあった町に
行くんとちゃうんか？
（ヴァッシュ）僕は
ニューオレゴンへ行きたいの
I wanna go to New Oregon!!
If you wanna go to Kansas,
go there by yourself!
行きたきゃ 君だけで行けば？
Say what?!
何やと！
Just shut up!!
（運転手）
いいから 黙れってんだよ
Oh, sorry!
（２人）あ… はいはい
（車の走行音）
（メリル）見事に
ボロボロですわね
This place was really hit hard.
（保安官）事の起こりは
よくある—
The local riffraff were
making trouble as usual...
チンピラどうしの
いざこざだった
...but then this guy
tried to step in, and voila!
だが そこへ—
男が仲裁に入ったと思ったら
このありさまさ
また くだらないトラブルに
首を突っ込みましたわね
He's gone and poked his nose
into more petty trouble.
Ma'am!
（ミリィ）せんぱーい
ヴァッシュさんが
どこにいるか分かりましたよ
I found out
where Mr. Vash is!
- Vash?!
- That's right, The Humanoid Typhoon...
（保安官）ヴァッシュ？
（メリル）そう
ヒューマノイド･タイフーン
...the man designated as
mankind's first human Act of God.
人類初の局地災害に
指定された人物です
That's absurd! He was weeping
and eating donuts at the same time!
そんなバカな！
あいつは泣きながら
ドーナツ食ってたんだぞ
こんな感じで
Like this!!
Donuts are his favorite food.
（メリル）彼の好物ですから
Are you serious?
This is the legendary gunman?
マジかよ
これが
あの伝説のガンマンだってのか
Where did you get
your information?
情報はどこで聞きまして？
It was all
over the satellite!
サテライトで放送してたんです
It said that he's
heading for New Oregon...
“ヴァッシュさんが
ニューオレゴンに向かって—”
...at 3,000 yarz an hour!
“毎時3000ヤーズのスピードで
進んでる”って
えらく細かい情報ですわね
That's awfully
detailed information.
（ミリィ）はい
Yes! It was advising everyone
in the area to be very careful!
“地域の人はくれぐれも
注意してください”って
言ってました
You can't be serious!
（フリス家の男Ａ）本気かよ
The day before yesterday, most of
the Polo Family went out of town...
（ルラウド）一昨日(いっさくじつ)から—
ポロ家のほとんどが
町を離れていて—
...leaving no one but
the fourth son, Slater.
残ってるのは
４男のスレーターだけだ
On top of that, the shuttle that
goes to New Oregon is passing through.
しかも おあつらえ向きに—
ニューオレゴンへの
定期便まで来るときた
A chance like this
doesn't come twice.
これ以上のチャンスは
二度とないな
Y-Yeah, but...
（フリス家の男Ｂ）
け… けどよ
I'll do it.
（ベンソン）俺はやるぜ
The Polo Family cannot be allowed
to run amok any longer! Right?!
（ベンソン）これ以上
ポロ家の好き勝手させてたまるか
そうだろ？
Right, sort of...
（フリス家の男Ｃ）
ま… まあな
We'll have Mr. Lurald
with us this time, after all.
今回は ルラウドさんも
いてくれることだし
Yeah...
あ… ああ
That settles it.
決まりだな
We'll meet here again
at sunup tomorrow.
では 明日の朝 日が昇ったとき
また ここで落ち合おう
（ＤＪ）いいから
黙って聞きやがれ
Shut up and listen up! Today,
I'm going to school you people!
今日 お前(めえ)らに
教えてやらあ
Today's lesson is about typhoons!
I reckon you don't know, so here goes!
お題は「タイフーンに
ついて」だ
あっあー
知らないだろうから
教えてやるが—
A typhoon is a little
windy phenomenon...
タイフーンてのは
風がビュンビュン吹いてきて—
... which can carry your houses
and kids off into the sky.
家(うち)やガキを
吹っ飛ばす現象なんだよ
Her name is Jacqueline!
This lovely young lady...
名前はジャクリーン
イカしたお嬢様が—
... has come to wipe you out!
おめえらを
なぎ払いに来たってえわけだ
What's this about a typhoon?
Are you expecting relatives?
何や？ タイフーンって
お前みたいなんが
もう１人来るんか？
意味 知らなかったの？
Don't you know
what a typhoon is?
A typhoon is a beauty
who levels entire cities.
タイフーンってのは
町をなぎ払う美女のことだよ
（ウルフウッド）うん… 美女？
A beauty?
アハッ ごっつそうやな ハハッ
She sounds tough.
- By the way, who's paying?
- You, of course.
ところで ここの払いは？
君持ち
Why me?! I gave in to your whining
and came all the way to New Oregon!
何でやねん
お前の言うこと聞いて—
ニューオレゴンくんだりまで
来たったんやで
I never asked you to!
頼んでない 頼んでない
うーん
This town looks peaceful,
but it's about to get bloody.
この町 平和そうに見えて—
結構
血なまぐさいことになっとるで
あ…
（ウルフウッド）
サテライトの利権めぐって—
The Polo and Fris Families
are still quarrelling...
ポロ家とフリス家の
いざこざが続いとるんや
...over the rights
to the satellite.
For example, a girl
distantly related to the Fris...
現に このあいだも—
フリス家の遠縁の娘が
殺されたらしいで
...was murdered.
（ヴァッシュ）え…
（ウルフウッド）ハア…
I don't want you pulling
another 'LittleJersey' here.
この前のリトルジャージーの
二の舞はごめんや
Let's git while
it's in one piece.
この町 破壊せんうちに
はよ出よ
（ヴァッシュ）うっ うっ うっ…
Don't cry!!
（ウルフウッド）泣くな！
But doesn't it make you sad?!
君は悲しくないのか？
Why do things like that happen?
どうして
そんなことが起こるんだろ？
ハア… どこにでも
転がっとるような話やんか
It's not like it's anything new...
Even the most peaceful folk
will take up arms if family is killed.
静観決めとこゆうやつも
肉親が殺されたら銃を取る
At any rate, let's go
before we get involved in...
とにかくや
面倒に巻き込まれんうちに…
（黒猫の鳴き声）
I always figured you
were no mere mortal...
（ウルフウッド）
前から普通の人間やないと
思っとったんやが—
...but I never imagined
you were a cat.
まさかネコやったとは…
Just a darned minute!
Where did that idiot get to?!
…って どこに行きよったんや？
あのアホは
Sir?
（ウエイター）お客さん
（ウルフウッド）ギクッ
Altogether,
your meal comes to $ $30.
お食事代
締めて30ダブドルです
- Put it on my tab.
- No dice.
（ウルフウッド）ツケといて
（ウエイター）ダメ
That rotten
Needle-noggin!
（ウルフウッド）
あの くされトンガリ
（ドアが開く音）
（ポロ家の男Ａ）坊ちゃん
Mr. Slater! There's a hick
outside asking to be shown in!
とぼけた野郎が
中に入れろと言ってきてるんですが
I'm not hiring,
and I don't give charity.
（スレーター）
物乞いや就職希望者に用はねえ
Send him away.
とっとと追い払え
A friend of mine works here...
（ヴァッシュ）
知り合いがここで働いてて
挨拶したいんですよ
...so I dropped by to say hi.
Don't come in
without my say-so!
か… 勝手に
入ってくんじゃねえ
- Who do you want to see?
- Max Simon!
（スレーター）
誰に会いたいって？
マックス･サイモン
Oh, that old codger?
（スレーター）
ああ あの偏屈ジジイか
Go ahead.
勝手にしな
Hey, thanks a lot.
すんませんねえ ホントに
ああっ いいんですかい？
Are you sure about this?
（スレーター）しかたねえだろ
What choice do I have? Even my
old man doesn't dare defy old Max.
あのジイさんには 親父(おやじ)ですら
頭が上がんねえんだからよ
We did the right thing to
splurge on a room in 2nd class!
（メリル）奮発して
二等客室を借りて正解でしたわね
The last time we rode one of these,
it was full of bandits.
（ミリィ）前 乗ったときは—
盗賊さんが いっぱいやってきて
チョー難儀でしたね
The experience was ruined!
ニューオレゴンで
あの人と会ったら—
If we run into him in New Oregon,
things will get busy again.
また忙しくなりますわよ
やっぱり
騒ぎに巻き込まれるんですかねえ
We're gonna get dragged
into stuff again, huh?
（２人）ガラガラ…
（発砲音）
（２人）ブーッ
Bandits!!!
（客）盗賊だー
Hands in the air!!
（フリス家の男Ａ）
黙って手を上げろ！
Don't try anything funny!
Got that?!
妙なマネは
ご法度にしてもらう
いいな！
（メリルとミリィ）
またですわ！
Not again!!
フフフフッ
命が惜しけりゃ
全員おとなしくしてろ
All of you behave,
if you value your lives!
ううっ
あっ！
Please, don't move.
頼むから動かないでくれ
Help will arrive for you later.
そうすれば いずれ助けが来る
If you stop this now,
the law will be more lenient.
ここでやめれば
罪も軽くなりましてよ
I gave up my life
a long time ago.
（ベンソン）
命なんてとっくに捨ててる
それに ここで引けないわけが
俺にはあるんだ
And besides, there's a good
reason I can't pull back now.
え？
We're almost at our destination!
Look after things here!
もうすぐ予定時刻だ
ここは頼んだぞ
Got it!
（フリス家の男Ｃ）おう
If she were alive,
she'd be your age.
生きてりゃあ同じ年頃だな…
（メリル）ああ…
（マックス･サイモン）うーん
（ノックする音）
I'm not through with
the forecast yet! Beat it!
予報はまだ終わっとらん
とっととうせろ
You haven't changed
a bit, old man.
相変わらずだね ジイさん
Vash?!
（マックス）
ヴァッシュ！ 久しぶりだな
It's been a long time!
What happened to your usual threads?
どうした いつもの服は？
I kind of wore them out.
ボロボロになっちゃってさ
（マックス）ヘヘッ
So you've come to peek up
Jacqueline's skirt, have you?
ジャクリーンのスカートの下を
のぞきに来たってわけか
Has it really been 10 years
since you last came home?
しかし お前が戻るの
10年ぶりかのう
（ヴァッシュ）エヘッ
（衝撃音）
（ヴァッシュ）うわあ！
（マックス）う… うっ！
What was that?
何じゃ？
（フリス家の男Ａ）
ポロ家の４男坊を見つけるんだ
Find the Polo boy!
（発砲音）
（ポロ家の男Ｂ）ぐわあ！
（フリス家の男Ｂ）抵抗するやつは
殺してもかまわねえぞ
Kill anyone who resists!
（男たちの争う声）
（ベンソン）
やつはどこだ？ やつは
Where is he?! I want him!!
Holy cow! A monster idiot just
crashed my exalted place of work!!
（ＤＪ）おーっと
偉大な俺様の仕事場に
突っ込んできやがった—
大バカ野郎がいるぜ
居眠り運転にしちゃあ
度が過ぎてるんじゃねえか？
I've heard of falling asleep at
the wheel, but this is ridiculous!
あ？
（ＤＪ）うわっ 坊ちゃん
Mr. Slater?
（発砲音）
（２人の悲鳴）
（市民のどよめき）
Pardon me, coming through...
（ウルフウッド）はいはい
ちょっくら ごめんなさいよっと
おー 殴り込みかいなあ
Ooh, it's a raid!
あ痛(いて)っ あ痛(いて)て…
Citizens of this town,
listen carefully.
（ルラウド）
市民の諸君 よーく聞け
サテライトの施設は
我々フリス家が占拠した
We, the Fris, have seized
the satellite facility!
The injustice and hardships
we suffered at the hands...
これは不当なるポロ家の圧力に
辛酸をなめ続けた—
... of the grasping Polo Family
have led to our crusade!
我々の起こした聖戦である
要求は１つ
We have but one demand!
Bring us the head of the Polo Family!
ポロ家の当主を
ここに連れてくることだ
We have a guest he should meet.
それなりのゲストも用意している
（スレーター）はっ 助けて…
Help me... Help me!
（市民のざわめき）
（スレーター）助けてくれー！
（ウルフウッド）
そういうことかい
So that's how it is.
If our demands are not met
within three days...
（ルラウド）３日後までに
要求を聞き入れない場合は—
... I cannot guarantee his safety.
命の保証はしない
The head of the family
is in Neo Colorado.
当主はネオ･コロラドだ
He'll never make it
back in three days.
３日じゃ
戻ってくることはできんぞ
Are you going in?
行くのか？
I guess this is
just my nature.
こういうのを
性分っていうんですかね
ふん やったぜ
あとはポロ家をやって—
All right. Now all we
have to do is kill Polo...
...useJacqueline for cover,
and make tracks.
ジャクリーンに紛れて
トンズラするだけだ
Jacqueline?
ジャクリーン
That's the name of the typhoon
heading for this town, little lady.
この町に近づいてきている
タイフーンの名前だよ
お嬢ちゃん
“タイフーン”って
本物のことじゃない
He's talking about
a real typhoon.
How in the world did
you mix that up, Milly?
どこをどう聞き間違えたんですの？
ミリィ
It fooled me completely!
Darn it!!
見事にだまされました
悔しーい
That's not what
I want to hear!
（メリル）
そうじゃないで… しょっ！
（衝撃音）
（フリス家の男Ｃ）うおっ！
（フリス家の男Ｃ）
ううっ ああ…
Let's go, Milly!
（メリル）行きますわよ ミリィ
（ミリィ）はい
Yes, ma'am!
- You bitch!!
- Take that!
この女(あま)
（ミリィ）えい！
（銃声）
（フリス家の男Ｃ）あちゃ おお…
しっ 白だった…
Th-They were... white.
（フリス家の男Ｄ）
人質は抑えたらしい
They're holding down
the hostages.
He says we can do
whatever we want with the others.
残ったやつらを
好きにしていいとよ アハハッ
（フリス家の男Ｅ）
ヘヘッ　そんじゃ
サービスタイムといこうぜ
Okay then, let's
go get our perks!
That sounds rather unsettling.
（ヴァッシュ）
ずいぶん物騒なことを言うねえ
（フリス家の男たち）あ？
おお…
Are you still
doing things this way?
まだこんなやり方しとるのか？
Uh, well, yeah...
え… ええ…
（銃声）
（フリス家の男Ｆ）
あっ！ あ… ああ
A Polo bodyguard?!
（フリス家の男Ｇ）
ポロ家の用心棒か？
No, already!
（ヴァッシュ）
そんなんじゃないって
If you have a death wish,
try to take us down!
命がいらんのなら
かかってくるがいい
But I hope you're aware that
this man is Vash the Stampede!
この男が—
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードだと
分かっているんならな
（２人）なにっ！
What?!
（ヴァッシュ）ジ… ジイさん
Aw, come on...
Act the part.
They'll chicken out.
らしくふるまえ
そうすりゃ
やつらもビビって逃げる
You think so?
（ヴァッシュ）
そういうもんすかあ？
（２人）うわあ！
（ヴァッシュ）えっ？
（ベンソン）ハア ハア…
（フリス家の男たちの談笑）
（ベンソン）うっ！
（ベンソン）うっ…
（銃が震える音）
（ベンソン）ハア ハア…
うっ…
あっ…
Ease up.
（ルラウド）力みすぎだ
（ベンソン）ああ…
There's no one to shoot here.
Take your finger off the trigger.
もう敵はいねえ
トリガーから指を離しな
Right. Sorry.
あ… ああ　すまん
It's an emergency!!
（フリス家の男Ｇ）大変だー
（２人）ああ？
（ベンソン）どうした？
What is it?
It's Vash!
Vash the Stampede is coming!!
ヴァッシュだ　ここに—
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードが
やってくる
なんだと
What?!
But why? What is
Vash doing here?!
なんで… なんで
ヴァッシュがここにいるんだ？
This isn't funny!!
シャレになんねえぞ おい
Calm down!
落ち着け
ハア…
うわさには尾ひれが付くもんだ
Rumors are always exaggerated.
And even if he
is the real thing...
それに
たとえ本物だとしても—
...he has to take that passage
to get here. It's the only way in.
ここに来るためには
その通路を通ってくるしかねえ
一本道だ
Remember the reason
we chose this location.
俺たちが
ここを選んだ理由を思い出せ
あ… ああ
Oh, yeah...
（足音）
（フリス家の男Ｂ）ああ？
（フリス家の男Ｈ）き… 来た！
H-He's here!
（足音）
（ヴァッシュ）♪ 皆殺し 皆殺し
（フリス家の男Ｈ）くっ…
To-tal slaughter...
（ヴァッシュ）♪ １人も残さねえ
I won't leave a single...
... man alive...
La la la loo la,
genoci-i-ide...
♪ ラララルラ ジェノサイド
Lee lee loo lee loo,
an ocean of blood...
♪ リリルリル 血のオーシャン
Let's be-gin the...
♪ レッツ ビギンさ
...killing time!
♪ キリングターイム
- Hey, he's singing!
- What horrible lyrics!
（フリス家の男Ｇ）歌ってるぞ
（フリス家の男Ｈ）
なんてイヤな歌詞なんだ
Stand your ground!
It's just a bluff!
おたつくな
ただの はったりだ
（ヴァッシュ）あーあ
やっぱ こういうのダメだわ
I knew it wouldn't work.
Hey, can I ask you something?
ねえ １つ聞いていい？
Yeah, what?
（ルラウド）何だ？
Would you prefer to call off the game
like a sensible adult...
（ヴァッシュ）大人の判断で
このままノーゲームにするのと—
...or to get roughed up
and be out the game for good?
痛い目に遭って
ゲームオ−バーになるのと—
どっちがいい？
I'll see your question
with another question:
質問を質問で返すが—
Do you want
a belly full of lead?
てめえこそ
ハチの巣になりてえのか？
（ヴァッシュ）
残念　交渉決裂っすか？
That's a shame! We have
a negotiations breakdown.
（フリス家の男Ｂ）野郎！
Why, you!
（銃声）
うわっ だあ！
（爆発音）
な… なんて
でたらめな野郎だ
This guy can't be for real!
（男たちのどよめき）
（殴る音）
（フリス家の男Ｂ）でやっ
（フリス家の男Ｇ）おおっ
（殴る音）
（フリス家の男Ａ）おおーっ
Mr. Lurald...
ルラウドさん…
...is gone.
いない
（殴る音）
（フリス家の男Ｈ）んがっ
ハッ！
The fight's over.
Release the hostage.
もう勝負はついた
人質を放してくれ
（ベンソン）ダ… ダメだ
No!!
（殴る音）
（スレーター）あっ！
（ベンソン）感謝するよ
I'm grateful to you. Thanks
to you, now I can kill him!
あんたのおかげで
こいつをやることができる
I'll hit you, mister.
How can you make such a decision?
はたくぜ おっさん
そんなこと
なんであんたが決められんだよ
Now, come on. Let him...
なあ 頼むから その人を…
Forget it!!
（ベンソン）断る！
ええっ いいかげんに…
Would you knock it...
You know what he did?!
（ベンソン）こいつはなあ
（ヴァッシュ）あ…
He killed her!
（マックス）こいつは殺したんだ
He killed my daughter!!
俺の娘を殺したんだ！
（ベンソン）
こいつは娘の敵(かたき)なんだよ
He's going to pay
for the death of my daughter!!
（ウルフウッド）フゥー
We're not like God.
Not only are our powers limited...
わしらは神様と違うんや
万能でないだけに
鬼にもならなあかんときがある
... but we sometimes
have to play the devil.
How will you respond?
お前はどんな答え出すんや
うっ…
My daughter...
娘は… 娘は…
This is horrible.
Not again...
（男Ａ）ひでえ またかよ
（男Ｂ）フリス家の遠縁だからって
娘は無関係じゃねえか
I know she's related to the Fris,
but she had nothing to do with it!
Don't worry,
it'll be over soon!
（ベンソン）なーに すぐ済むさ
（ヴァッシュ）あっ
ああー！
（ベンソン）終わったら—
Once I'm done, you can
hand me over to the sheriff...
騎兵隊だろうが保安官だろうが
突き出してくれてかまわない
...or the cavalry
for all I care!
（スレーター）や… やめろ！
D-Don't do it!!
Please! I don't want to die!
頼む 死にたくない
許してくれー
Forgive me!!
Forgive me, please!!!
許してくれ！ お願いだー
（スレーターの泣き声）
Don't beg for your life!
She must have begged for hers!!
（ベンソン）命を惜しむな
うちの娘もしたはずだ
アイリーンはひどい状態だった
Aileen was in such
a pitiful state...
...no human being
could do such a thing!
あんなマネが
人間にできるはずない
You people...
You people aren't human!!
お前らは…
お前は人間じゃないんだよ！
ハー ハハハ
死にたくなーい
I don't want to die!!!
Stop it! Stop it!
やめて… やめてくれー
Animal!
鬼畜が！
（スレーター）
ああ… あああっ！
You can't!
（ヴァッシュ）ダメだ…
（ベンソン）娘の敵！
I will avenge her!!
（スレーター）
ヒャー ハハハ…
（２人のもみあう声）
Don't stop me!
Get your hands off me!!
（殴る音）
（ベンソン）邪魔するな 手を放せ
What do you know?!
お前に何が分かる
Don't use your
self-seeking justice on me!!
手前勝手な正義感で計るな
お前に俺の苦しみが
分かってたまるかあ！
You could never
understand how I feel!!
Let go of me!!
放せー！
うわあー
Daddy!
と… 父さーん
父さん…
Daddy! Daddy!
父さん… 父さーん
Daddy!
父さん… ああ…
How many times...
その言葉
俺の娘は何回言った？
...did my daughter
scream that word?!
No, don't shoot him!!
ダメだ 撃つな！
Don't kill him!
殺すな ううっ…
お願いだ 撃たないでくれー！
I beg you, don't shoot him!!!
（ベンソン）うっ… うう…
（ベンソンのすすり泣く声）
This is funny...
（ベンソン）
おかしいよ アイリーン
...Aileen.
I can't shoot him.
撃てないんだ
Why can't I?!
I want to avenge you...
なんでだよ
お前の敵なのに…
なんで撃てないんだよーっ！
...so why can't I shoot him?!
（ベンソンの泣き声）
Thank goodness.
よかった
え？
It's nothing. Let's get both
of them far away from here...
うん… 何でもありませんわ
騎兵隊が来る前に
２人を連れて ここを離れましょう
...before the cavalry arrives.
（市民のざわめき）
The shootout which began
just past noon today...
（ＤＪ）
正午すぎから始まったドンパチは
騎兵隊の一斉突入で無事解決
... was brought to a safe close
with one swift charge of the cavalry!
捕まったバカは12人
俺も含む人質も開放された
12 idiots were captured, and the
hostages, myself included, were freed.
ヒューマノイド･タイフーンが
関わったにしちゃあ—
For something involving The Humanoid
Typhoon, the damage wasn't that bad!
被害は少なかったな
But the day after tomorrow,
a real typhoon is coming to town!
だが あさってには
本物のタイフーンがやってくるぜ
Be very, very careful!
せいぜい気をつけるこったあ
Go easy on
the good guy stuff, okay?
（ウルフウッド）
ええ人ごっこも大概にせえや
Luck and persistence
won't work forever.
幸運や ごり押しは
いつまでも通用せえへんで
（ヴァッシュ）あ…
エヘッ
（ヴァッシュ）久しぶり
Long time, no see.
Yeah.
（メリル）ええ
I have found you.
（レオノフ･ザ･パペットマスター）
見つけました
I will take everything into
consideration, and reach a conclusion.
すべてを総合して結論します
（レオノフ）間違いありません
There is not a doubt.
Vash the Stampede
is on the move...
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードが
動き始めました
... Mr. Legato.
レガート様
♪〜
〜♪
In times of hardship,
in times of sadness...
（ヴァッシュ）
つらいことがあったとき
悲しいことがあったとき
...there is a place the traveller
can let his mind return to.
旅人が思いをはせる場所がある
Home.
それが ふるさとだ
I still don't know what kind
of a past the traveller abandoned...
どんな過去を捨てて—
旅人が ふるさとを離れたのか
今は分からない
...when he left
his home behind.
I still don't know what kind
of a sorrow he bears.
どんな悲しみを背負っているのか
今は分からない
But the traveller
can keep walking forward...
だが 旅人は—
自分を支えてくれるもの—
...because he has something which
sustains him, a place which accepts him.
自分を包んでくれる
場所があるから—
前へ歩きだせる
He can walk forward,
step by careful step.
一歩一歩踏みしめて
歩いていくことができる